CAREER PROFILE

Software Engineer with more than 4 years experience, specializing in back end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Look at myself as a Full Stack Developer, well-versed in numerous programming languages and also as time passes wish to be familiar with devops roles.

EXPERIENCES

Software Engineer

MobiCom, Bengaluru

Mar 2017 - Present

MobiCom is a demographic driven experiences and commerce solution provider, driving transactions, building an ecosystem around private club members, golfers and affluent credit card members worldwide.

Software Engineer

Vserv, Mumbai

Jan 2016 - Mar 2017

Jan 2014 - Jan 2016

Vserv a Mobile Advertising and Commerce Company, is the smart data platform for mobile marketing in India and SEA.

Software Developer

Medisurge, Mumbai

Medisurge Technologies Pvt Ltd is a digital health company with the objective of providing a single destination to users for all health care needs. Medisurge Technologies also markets its services as Top Doctors Online (TDO).

7 TOP SKILLS & PROFICIENCY

PHP	8/10
Javascript & jQuery	7.5/10
MySQL	7/10
HTML5 & CSS	7/10
GIT	8/10

SKILLS SET

Main: PHP, Git, JavaScript, AJAX, MySQL, HTML5, CSS

Backend Frameworks: Laravel, Yii, Slim, Codelgniter

Javascript Frameworks: Jquery

PHP Frontend Frameworks / Templating Engines: Blade, Twig

Payment Gateways: PayPal, CCAvenue, Stripe, Wirecard

Web Services: SOAP, WSDL, REST

Caching Techniques: APC, Memcache, XCache

Operating System: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu)



Uday Karkera
Full Stack Developer
4 Years Exp

- uday.karkera@gmail.com
- **C** 09819131365 (Ban)
- **1** 09821592988 (Mum)
- 🚷 udaykarkera.github.io

in

linkedin.com/in/udaykarkera

- github.com/udaykarkera
- @karkera_uday

EDUCATION

BSc in Information Technology Mumbai University 2010 - 2013

Aircraft Maintenance Engineering Bombay Flying Club, Juhu 2006 - 2009

H.S.C. Examination Gokuldham High School & Jr. College, Goregaon 2004 - 2006

S.S.C. Examination Yashodham High School, Goregaon 2004

LANGUAGES

English (Professional)

Hindi (Professional)

Marathi (Professional)

Tulu (Native)

Kannada (Learning)

INTERESTS

Development Web Server: WAMP, XAMPP, LAMP, Vagrant

Web Hosting: Apache, Nginx

Version Control System: Git

Methodologies: Agile Scrum

Others: Bootstrap, JSON, XML, .htaccess, W3C Markup Validation

IDE / Editor / Tools: diffuse, Csv, Excel, EmEditor, Gearman, Meld, NetBeans, Nano, Notepad++, Postman, Word, Sublime Text, Vim



MobiCom Technologies Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru

OneCardNet: OneCardNet provides Bank card holders a platform to shop, dine, etc with different offers

- · Designed from "scratch".
- · Maitainance & Optimistation of the Web and Apis
- · Monitoring technical aspects of OneCardNet

Green Golf: A responsive website template designed to book time slots by Golfers choosing different Golf Courses across the world.

- Setup of the Laravel project across different environments
- Maitainance & Optimistation of the Web and Apis
- Payment Gateway (Wirecard)
- · Monitoring technical aspects of Greengolf

OneClubNet: OneClubNet enables private clubs and their members worldwide to engage, network, create new experiences and transact, driving revenue for the clubs while delivering value for members.

· Maitainance & Optimistation of the CMS and Apis

Others:

- · Set GIT process across all verticals
- Conducting PHP, MySQL Interviews

Vserv Digital Services Pvt Ltd, Mumbai

RTB: Real Time Bidding is one of the verticals of VSERV where advertising inventory is bought and sold on a per-impression basis, via programmatic instantaneous auction, similar to financial markets.

- Integration setup with Real Time Bidding (RTB) Partners.
- Modifications, Maintenance, Optimisation of Applications & Websites.
- Implement Yii Apc Caching.
- · Scrapping Sites.

Medisurge Technologies Pvt Ltd, Mumbai

Telcom: Medisurge provides health content and services (VAS) to Telcoms.

- Manage Telcom Activities & Developers Team
- Billing integration setup with Telecommunications Vodafone, Airtel, Idea (in India), Etisalat, du (in UAE)
- WURFL (Mobile Device Detection) Integration
- Payment Gateway (CCAvenue, PayPal)
- S2S Integration setup with Advertising Networks i.e. Kimia, Tyroo, Mobusi, Inmobi, Mobvista, Avazu, Yeahmobi, etc
- Managing Links. Mapping and tracking of links (.htaccess)
- Automated XML generation application To display content on Vodafone Mobile Site.
- · Optimsation of existing product.
- Telcom Reports Application

TDO: Top Doctors Online aims to provide 3 key constituents of health care needs – Information (Content), Doctor Consultation and access to key health services at a single destination.

- · Maintenance of Website.
- Integrate Google Maps API.

GENERAL

DOR: 1/4th Nov. 1988

Nationality: Indian

Sex: Male

Marital Status: Unmarried

Others:

• Conducting PHP, MySQL Interviews

Freelancing

Upwork: A global freelancing platform where businesses and independent professionals connect and collaborate remotely.

- Server Mangement Application: Customers, Servers, Server online offline updates.
- Staff Mangement Application: Login logout app, Attendance system, Salary calci, Individual Work, etc.
- Integrate Zopim livechat.
- W3C Validation of Web pages.